LAUREN CIULLA DESIGNER / / DEVELOPER

Lauren is a multifaceted designer and developer in NYC. Combining passion for creativity with experience in visual design, frontend development, user research, and content creation, she helps clients express themselves and their ideas through digital content.

CONTACT

M lauren-ciulla.com



lauren.m.ciulla@gmail.com



Inkedin.com/in/lauren-ciulla



(203) 260 - 2013

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT 2016 - 2020 BA / / DIGITAL MEDIA & DESIGN

Graduated summa cum laude from Honors Program.

Earned a concentration in Web & Interactive Media.

Published Honors Thesis titled "User Research and Real User Problems: Improving the User Experience of Online Shopping."

BA / / ENGLISH

Graduated summa cum laude.

UNIVERSITY OF RICHMOND Jan 2019

Winter Study Abroad Program in Rome, Italy.

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER Jul 2017

Summer Study Abroad Program in London, UK.

TRUMBULL HIGH SCHOOL 2012 - 2016

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Graduated from Honors Program with a 4.66/4.0 GPA.

HONORS & AWARDS

New England Scholar Award 2020

Aetna Undergraduate Writing in the

Disciplines Honorable Mention

Babbidge Scholar Award 2018 & 2019

2020

Sophomore Honors 2018

Alpha Lambda Delta

Honor Society 2016 - 2020

SKILLS

Illustrator / / After Effects / / Premiere Pro Photoshop / / InDesign / / HTML / / CSS JavaScript / / PHP / / Procreate / / InVision Sketch / / MailChimp / / WordPress

WORK EXPERIENCE

VISUAL DESIGNER / / IBM

Aug 2020 - Present

Incorporate graphic design, animation, user experience design, and original content creation to make an impact on products and services IBMers use every day.

Conduct user research, IBM Enterprise Design Thinking activities, and user testing throughout the design process to pinpoint user needs and ensure user-centered design.

CIO DESIGN INTERN / / IBM

May 2019 - Aug 2020

Developed research-based content, UX, and visual design for a resource to help designers work effectively in Agile and a website to guide interns through onboarding. Created graphics, illustrations, and animated videos for display on IBM social channels and in CIO Design office spaces.

DESIGN INTERN / / Greenhouse Studios

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Designed and developed web solutions for virtual reality projects, including an immersive web narrative and a progressive web application in the Vue.js framework.

SENIOR EMAIL MARKETING INTERN EMAIL MARKETING INTERN / / UConn Foundation

Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

Nov 2017 - Aug 2019

Formulated digital engagement strategies encompassing timelines and content for multichannel engagement (email, social, web) to promote sporting/recreational events.

Executed email campaigns by designing emails to accentuate various calls to action, A/B testing variable content to maximize performance, and analyzing email reports to synthesize them into user-friendly content recommendations.

DIGITAL GRAPHIC ARTIST &

WEB DEVELOPER / / UConn Communication Dept.

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019

Implemented original graphics, illustrations, and JavaScript code to improve the UI/UX of an educational video game.

FREELANCE DESIGNER & MARKETING INTERN / / HPOne

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019 May 2018 - Aug 2018

Designed and coded animated HTML5 banner ads featured in Google AdWords slots.

Created Medicare-focused infographics with original content, graphics, and illustrations for content marketing material.

Organized, advertised, and executed events to promote engagement and recruitment.

INVOLVEMENT & LEADERSHIP

DESIGN THINKING WORKSHOP FACILITATOR / / Girls Who Code

Aug 2019

Lead students through Design Thinking activities to promote rapid ideation, Agile methodologies, and creativity.

WEB SPECIALIST / / Digital Media & Design AgencyX Team Aug 2019 - May 2020

Conducted a heuristic review of the UConn DMD website, implemented changes to improve UX, and migrated site content to a CMS to simplify future site maintenance.

DESIGNER / / IBM CIO Design & DWE Hackathon

Jul 2019

FRONTEND DEVELOPER / / UConn Digital Experience Lab Sep 2018 - May 2019

Designed and developed digital solutions including a wayfinding app and an interactive children's museum exhibit on student-run Agile teams.